Please insert coins.
The fighting is over, and the big hole in
the protective wall is plugged for now.
We finished off the monsters that invaded,
and we're working around the
clock to fully repair the wall.
Once that's done, the Clearflow Lake
Stratum Village should be safe again.
Thanks for all your work, Hulemy.
How's the transfer circle stuff going?
I think I pretty much got it figured out.
Even if it's not fully
operational, it's almost there.
We'll be able to send a few people.
What a delicious-looking treat.
Would you mind if I had one of those?
It's exquisite.
By the way,
you wouldn't happen to know where
Director Bear is at the moment, would you?
There's still the sunken area near the
wall, and we'll need to deal with it first.
Oh, you mean the spot where Boxo turned
building size and dropped in from above?
Apparently, the hole I made is interfering
with the reconstruction efforts.
Wait a minute. That shape.
I have an idea!
On the outside, I'm just a big metal box,
but inside, I've still got a human soul!
In this new world of wonders,
I travel to and fro on the back
of my super strong partner,
Lamas.
The name's Boxxo. Hello there.
That means yes, by the way.
Thank you.
I'm finally back.
That was exhausting.
This morning's rubble
removal duty took forever.
I'm so tired.
I'm done over here as well.
There's hardly any air circulation
in the transfer chamber.
If I work in that oven much
longer, I'll shrivel up.
I need something nice and refreshing.
Boxo, give me a cold one.
Boxo, where are you running off to?
Boxo, come back here.
Boxo.
Hold on, Boxo!
Something cold!
Please, Boxo!
Boxo, wait!
I got you!
That looks like so much fun!
Come on, Hilary, let's get in, too!
Hey, hold on! Yahoo!
The water's nice and refreshing.
Oh, good grief.
All right.
Everyone's having fun.
Hey, Swori, why aren't you getting in?
The water feels great.
No, thank you.
I'm not really in the
mood to swim right now.
What did you do that for?
Making a temporary pool
turned out to be a good idea.
It went over better than ever expected.
It was decided we'd hold a summer
festival to give the villagers
and hunters a chance to let
loose after all the fighting.
Our resources are limited,
so the party is small.
But I thought everybody could
use a bit of a distraction.
This sort of thing is the reason
why Director Bear is in charge.
Boxo, ice cream, please. Me too!
Ice cream, huh?
Sorry, but at a summer festival, it's
gotta be this. Let's go! Form change!
Shaved ice machine!
Come and get it!
Oh, what is this, Boxo?
Some sort of new product?
It's click!
Objectively speaking,
the quality of the ice the vending
machine outputs isn't great.
However, this is where
my skills come into play!
I'll shave the ice so
it's like powdery snow!
Then I'll add lots of
fresh syrup on top of it.
The shaved ice has a distinctive look
that just makes you want to try it.
It's really cold and sweet.
The shaved ice is so fluffy and it melts
in your mouth as soon as you eat it.
It's delicious.
Yeah, I bet it is.
I only wish that I had access to
more than three kinds of syrup.
I know.
First, some apple slices from
an apple vending machine.
Apples and other fruits can be used
as toppings for the shaved ice.
Voila!
Just like that, it's been leveled up!
Hey, Boxo, what are you selling?
Some kind of sweet snack
with fruit and ice.
It looks really tasty.
The hunters' association is picking up
the tab for all the food and drink today?
so you can enjoy as much as you want.
What kind of magic item
would Boxo be classified as?
It's not like he's a weapon or armor.
If I had to say, he'd be an
all-purpose goods-supplying magic item.
That's way too long.
How about calling him an
all-purpose magic item?
Vending machine.
Huh?
You're saying you're a vending machine?
Yeah, yeah.
I was trying to say vending
machine, but that's what came out.
I suppose it'll have to do for now.
Hey, Boxo?
Can we talk?
Remember that guy you captured
who destroyed my village?
Last night, Director Bear told me that
he gave him the punishment he deserved.
And now, I don't feel like
I have a purpose anymore.
The only reason she became
a hunter in the first
place was to get stronger
so she could get revenge.
What should I even say here?
Look at me, reduced to a
simple vending machine.
It's certainly not ideal.
But I treasure the time I've spent
with Llamas and everyone else.
I wouldn't trade it for anything.
That's why.
Yeah, you're right, Voxo.
You'll stay by my side until
the very end, won't you?
Yeah, yeah.
No more moping.
After all, there are still plenty
of things left for us to do.
Hello there.
Fortunately, Hulemy and Shimelai got
the transfer circle working again.
You're amazing, Hulemy.
Thanks, but it's not fully functional yet.
It's kind of limited to the
dungeon and only goes to one spot.
Also, we can only transfer
about three people at most.
After much thought, we've decided
where that transfer point should be.
within the Origin Stratum.
The reason we ended up choosing
the Origin Stratum is because
it's the only one that leads
directly out of the dungeon.
It would make evacuating residents
much easier in case of emergency.
As for the three people we'll be sending
over, I'd like for you to go, Hulemy.
Right.
I'll need to be there in order to link
it back to the Transfer Circle here.
Excellent.
I'd like Lamas and Boxo to go as well.
Your skills will come in handy,
especially Boxo's ability to make food.
That'll be invaluable.
Sure, sounds good.
I've been wanting to check in on the
orphanage and the Menagerie of Fools.
You in, Boxo? Yes.
As long as I can help, I'm more
than happy to come along. Thank you.
And since Boxo doesn't count
toward the transfer limit,
we should be able to fit one more.
I'll accompany them.
Oh, it's Mishuel. You're volunteering?
I'll do what I can.
How reassuring.
I'm still only able to
speak to you, Master Boxo,
and maybe a little bit
to Lamas and Yulani.
What would I do if you all left?
Oh yeah, that makes sense.
I apologize for placing
this heavy burden on you.
I wish you luck.
Please be careful.
Alright, off we go!
These footprints were made
by humans, not monsters.
When the circle wouldn't open, they
must have turned around and left.
Stab anything you can
reach with those spears!
Don't line up with those
arrows either, okay?
If you start to get tired,
rotate out! On your left!
Roaring strike!
Yike! Ah!
That's not that bad. Who knows?
We might actually get
somewhere with today's attack.
Captain!
Reinforcements are here!
I won't say no to some help!
God damn!
I gotta say, you guys are a sight for
sore eyes! Hey, you lot! Come over!
Food's here!
So cold! So good!
It's been days since we had
something decent to eat!
You guys saved us!
Look at them go!
They'll eat through everything in no time!
I'll worry about that later.
For now, I'll just focus on
making sure everybody's fed.
You're seriously a lifesaver.
We were nearly done for back there.
I was about to start pulling out some
worst-case scenario contingencies.
What's he talking about?
No, I think I'd rather not know.
I can't thank you enough,
Boxo. You're the man.
What's up?
Huh?
The stairs to the surface?
Hold on!
Are we having a conversation?
So, you finally learned how to talk?
Yeah!
Sorry, I'll have to
update you on Boxo later.
Doesn't this stratum have a stairway
that connects to the surface?
Why didn't you leave the
dungeon if things were this bad?
We couldn't.
The huge door in front of the stairway
was shut tight and wouldn't budge an inch.
Our only choice was to dig our heels in
here and try to hold
out as long as possible.
I see.
Boxxo!
Give me vote!
Hang on, Shui!
Hardly anyone in the Origin
Stratum has experience.
Even against just those green
fiends, we had a lot of casualties.
They might have been in real trouble if
we showed up even a little bit later.
Right, Akka?
Yep, that's right, Shiro.
And we were nearly out of provisions,
so we might have been in real
trouble if Boxxo hadn't shown up.
That was great.
I'll give it another.
Thank you for the food.
You should slow down, Shui.
The food's not going anywhere.
Yeah, plus it's bad manners.
Sorry about that.
Boxxo, thanks again.
Yeah, Boxxo.
We can't thank you enough
for everything you've done.
Hello there.
I'm just happy that everybody's okay.
I too.
They say that when the school director
came back through the transfer circle,
she single-handedly
drove off all the nearby
monsters all right then once hula me does
her thing and gets the
transfer circle working
again we can evacuate
everybody to the clear
flow lake stratum sure
thing leave it to me
ah yeah feels good to
finally eat my film this
box will hear of a hero
so then what should we
do while hula me's
working oh yeah about that
Talk about time.
Oh, Director Origin.
It's been quite some time.
The magic item known as Boxo.
We owe you a debt of gratitude.
Please accept my sincerest thanks.
The transfer circle is in your
hands, magic item engineer Hulemy.
Oh, sure.
Everyone, heed my words.
It's unwise for us to stay
in this stratum any longer.
We should prioritize survival and take
temporary refuge in the
Clearflow Lake Stratum.
To that end, we must protect this village.
The transfer circle is
our only path forward.
Just be patient a little while longer.
We will overcome this together!
I've never noticed it before,
but Director Origin seems
especially popular with the men.
The next day,
a search party set out for
a prison located northeast
of the village to see if
anyone had taken refuge there.
Lamas and I volunteered to go along.
Director, what kind of bad
guys were held in the prison?
Ordinary criminals are kept in jail
cells within the Hunter Association.
But those who are imprisoned in
that place are irredeemable scum,
like mass murderers or
people who kill for pleasure.
Also, any word on that
particular prisoner?
He refuses to change his behavior, so
he's still locked up in the prison.
Who are you talking about?
An extreme pervert.
He has a rather unique nature.
We've received countless
complaints about him.
What exactly does he do?
He's not a criminal, per se,
but it was partly his idea to
be imprisoned in that place.
He wanted to be imprisoned?
It doesn't matter.
That degenerate is like a cackloach.
It'll take more than a
few monsters to kill him.
A cat cloach?
Oh, that must mean cockroach here.
Whatever the case, we still have to check.
Something's wrong.
Where are the prisoners?
The cells are all completely empty.
What's going on here?
What's this?
Is somebody out there? Of course.
You're alive.
You pathetic excuse for a clergyman.
Huh? Clergyman?
You needn't be so cruel.
I'm simply living true to my instincts.
Oh, this?
It's nothing concerning.
I adore well-worn footwear.
Whether it be men's or
women's, it doesn't matter.
But rest assured, I have no interest
in the person wearing them whatsoever.
ever.
Disgusting.
How did you manage to amass such a large
collection while being held in prison?
It's gotten noticeably colder as of late,
so I was using these
in place of a blanket.
Ah,
the monsters were causing such a fuss,
so I went ahead and opened all the cells,
releasing the poor prisoners
from their bondage.
You idiot!
Do you know what those
criminals are capable of?
I'm intimately aware of their crimes.
That's why I employed various
illusions and magic To attract the
monsters when I did it I thought it
might benefit the citizenry surely
you must be Joking he isn't he's not
the type to crack wise about this
kind of thing oh my if it isn't my
Dear friend Shui how long has it
been since we last talked first off
I'm not your friend I was Wondering
why we hadn't seen you lately
and it's because you've been here
wait they know each other I'm really
sorry about this director Origin
you see I love right this oddball
is a part of the Menagerie of Fools?
He's actually our healer.
A total weirdo who happens to be
good with mind altering magic.
Don't misunderstand.
One's footwear is a mirror
that reveals their life.
and through it, I can learn everything!
about their past and personality.
I want to touch their history
and ponder the implications.
Oh brother, this guy really is a pervert.
That's why I have no use for
pristine virginal footwear.
Give me shoes worn down to
the soles that tell a story.
The smelly boots of a hunter whose ripe
history oozes from the laces itself.
Only then can I know
what happiness truly is!
Listen, I get you're into them, but you
can't just steal other people's footwear!
Of course, theft is one of
the worst sins one can commit.
As I serve the divine, I will not
stray from the righteous path.
That's what makes this
guy such a nuisance.
He'll badger the owner
of whatever shoe he's
obsessing over until they
give in and sell it to him.
I get the privilege to peer into history.
Naturally, I'm happy to
pay a fair price for it.
I don't like how he
sometimes sounds reasonable.
So yeah, this guy's name is Heavy, and
he's as capable as he is troublesome.
Around 80 % of the Menagerie of Fools'
bad reputation is because of him.
Heavy, if you're a member of the
Menagerie of Fools, then tell me.
When the monsters attacked, why
did you do nothing to try to help?
I make it a rule not
to get in over my head.
After all, there's only so
much a single person can do.
However, I didn't just let everyone die.
Alright, allow me to explain.
Using illusions and magic that masks one's
presence, I managed to keep them hidden.
I wanted to save more people,
but this is all I could pull
off in the heat of the moment.
Amazing I couldn't sense anybody at
all are we safe who are these people
can we come out now Director Sir
Heavy you saved all of these people
I apologize Heavy it seems
that I judged you too soon
Oh, pay it no mind.
No, I insist.
Please, name your reward.
Don't hold back.
You deserve it. Very well.
Those boots you're wearing
would do just fine.
Nope.
Turns out she judged him
right the first time.
When we brought the survivors
back to the village,
they were happy to be reunited
with their loved ones.
Here you go.
I gratefully accept.
I can already smell the
sultry scent of your feet.
Incredible.
I can feel the history.
That said,
you can rest assured, my interest is
directed solely at your footwear, not you.
You weren't really my type.
I see your predilections
are as perverse as ever.
It'll be nice to have a
healer in the party again,
but I can't really say I'm
thrilled that he's back.
Director, here.
Sorry about him. Oh, wait.
I can't go back on my word. You sure?
Need to give this guy footwear.
What did he say?
I'm curious, too, but I think
we're better off not knowing.
It's a shame.
When he's not like this,
he's a great healer.
I agree, Aka.
He saved our hides a couple of times.
Well, the two of you have
always put up with his antics.
Of course, because why not?
Anyway, it's been a while since this many
from the Menagerie of Fools were together.
That's true.
Every one of you is such a free spirit,
it makes it hard to lead sometimes.
What's with those you're wanting
to talk looks on your faces?
Heavy may have some personality flaws, but
he's apparently a huge help in a fight.
Having a healer with you
is a pretty big deal.
Good evening, Boxo.
Could I please have some warm tea?
Hello there!
Hmm,
I don't really recognize
any of these products,
but I think Lamas recommended this one.
Wait, stop!
Oh, is something amiss?
I can tell just by looking
that's a boot, not a cup! I see.
Could it be that you're worried
the tea might leak out of this?
Fear not, friend.
I've put a cup inside to prevent spills.
Oh, that's fine, then.
Wait! No, it isn't!
By the way, this piece was
worn around for 12 years.
Its original owner was a
hunter whose experience
and sweat have permeated this rare gem,
though I did give it a good cleaning.
Well, at least that's something.
I mean, you only get about a week at most
to enjoy the scent. Hey, take it back.
He's a total pervert.
A talking magic item, huh?
From what I hear, you've got a human
soul inside of you. Yes. I see.
It would seem that fate has put you
in quite an unenviable position.
That said, perhaps you should be a
little more easygoing about things.
I mean, just look at you.
You're so wound up that
your heart is a rock.
Thank you.
I was hoping for more of
a laugh than a thank you.
Well, you only get to live once, right?
Might as well do things
that bring you happiness.
Also, it's hard to say why, but I
sense a kindred spirit within you.
As fellow special hobbyists,
we understand each other.
No, you don't.
It's not true.
I'll deny that with my dying beep.
Let's do it.
I look forward to serving you again.